Finding Aid for the Ami Aloni Papers LSC.2406
UCLA Library Special Collections
Ami Aloni papers
1973-1999
UCLA Library Special Collections
Aloni, Aminadav, 1928-1999
Aloni, Daniel
Meshi, Dori Aloni
Aloni, David
LSC.2406
11.7 linear feet (18 boxes)
The materials consist of written music, scores, and assorted paperwork related to the career of composer Ami Aloni. Aloni worked as a music director and composer for the film and television industry.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of David Aloni, Dan Aloni, and Dori Aloni Meshi, 2019.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9996973058406533
Biographical History
Aminadav "Ami" Aloni (1928-1999) moved to New York at the age of 18, where he studied piano and composition at The Juilliard School of Music. Aloni moved to Los Angeles in the 1950s to work in the film and television industry. He served as music director and composer on television programs, telethons, and films. His work has been featured in various productions including The Great Waldo Pepper, Roots, and Exodus. He served at Valley Beth Shalom in Encino for 25 years as Music Director. Aloni also directed the synagogue choir. His compositions written for the synagogue include more than 100 commissions for the liturgy and dramatic work, which are performed in synagogues and concert halls across the United States and throughout the world.
Source: biographical information provided by donors, 2019.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of written music, scores, and assorted paperwork related to the career of composer Ami Aloni and include examples of his work as a music director and composer for the film and television industry where he worked on television series, telethons, and films. The collection also includes materials related to Aloni's 25 years working as music director and choir leader for Valley Beth Shalom in Encino. Also included are his over 100 commissioned compositions, which are performed in synagogues and concert halls throughout the world.
Composers -- United States -- Archives; Television music -- Scores; Motion picture music -- Scores; Aloni, Daniel; Meshi, Dori Aloni; Aloni, David; Aloni, Aminadav, 1928-1999 -- Archives
- Stamp me in your heart, undated (Box 1, Folder 1, Box 18)
- Shalom Rav (score + parts), undated (Box 1, Folder 2, Box 18)
- Ta-amei S'pharad - original, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Old-New Shabbat Shacharit, 1995; 1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Ta'a'mei S'pharad, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Nate Lam - Orchestra parts, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Transcontinental Pub, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Song of Songs, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
- Nate Lam, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- The sound of my lover, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
- At night, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
- The King, undated (Box 18, Folder 6)
- Sylvia's commission - For Sylvia, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Aloni Music Foundation Professional membership packet, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Ahavat Olam for High Holidays, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Al Hanisim, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- A moment, an hour, a lifetime, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Ana Hashem, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ashrei, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Bar'chu, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Birkat Hachodesh, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Birth Is a beginning, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- B'Motsaeu M'nucha, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- B'Rosh Hashanah, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Chanukah Medley, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- A Chanukah Recipe, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Chassidic Service, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Circles of Love, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Consolations of Isaiah, undated (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- Dances of Love (Rikudim shel ahavah), undated (Box 3, Folder 4, Box 18, Folder 7)
- David's song, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Dirshuni Vichuyu, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Divrei Torah, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Ruth, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Esa Enai El Heharim, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Et Echezeh (from Circle of Love), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Et Ezkerah Yom (from Circle of Love), 1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- For all G-d's Children, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Gilgul shel Kadish, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Go Eat your Bread with Joy, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Gone are the Days, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Hachamah (Songs from Home), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Hallel, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
- Hal'luyah, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Hama-ariv Aravim, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Ha-osek B'tsorchei Tsibur, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Hashkivenu (High Holidays), undated (Box 4, Folder 12, Box 5, Folder 1)
- Hatshuka Lih'yot Ishah (from Circle of Love), 1986 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Uvtsel Knafecha (Hashkivenu), undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Havi Ladonai, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Hayaldah Hazot, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Hayashan Yitchadesh, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Hinach Yafa Ra-ayati, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Imi, Zichronah Livrachah, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Jazz Service, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
- Jubilee (Israel Independence), 1988 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- K'dushah, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- K'nachal Eitan, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Koheleth, undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- K'shem shenichnas Labrit, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
- L'Cha Dodi (Songs from Home), undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
- L'Chu N'Ran'nah, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- L'Dor Vador, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Listen with your Heart, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Ma Enosh (Yizkor), undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Magen Avot, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Ma Tovu, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Maynard's Nigun, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
- May the Words, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Mi Adir, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Mibeit Imi, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Mi Chamocha, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Michelson's Service, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Mirror Eyes, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Mi Sheberach, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Modim Anachnu Lach, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Musaf L'Shabbat, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Miriam, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- My Baby Brother Moses, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Nate's 1994 Commission (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Ner Adonai-Nishmat Adam, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Next Week - Esther, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Noah, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- The Old New Service, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- One Song ago, undated (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Or Ha-Am, undated (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Passages (old lyrics), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Passages (new lyrics), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Pirkei Chayim, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Pitchu Li, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Please help me live, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Psalm 23 (Yizkor Service), undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Rabbotai Nevarech (Birkat Hamazon), undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- R'fa-ebu V'nerafe, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Rise my love, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
- R'tseh, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Ruth, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Set me as a seal, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- S'fatai Tiftach, undated (Box 9, Folder 2-3)
- Shabbat Morning, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Shalom Rav, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- She is always there, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Sheva Brachot, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Shir Chadash, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Shiviti, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Sh'ma B'ni, 1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Sh'ma Koleinu, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Shomeir Yisrael, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Sim Shalom, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
- S'lichot, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
- Somech Noflim, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Songs Ascent, undated (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- Songs from Home, undated (Box 10, Folder 8, Box 11, Folder 1)
- Stamp me in your heart, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
- S'u Sharim, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
- For Sylvia, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Ta-amei S'pharad, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Tavas Z'Havi, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
- T'filah L'medinat Yisrael, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
- The Vow, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
- This is the Day, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
- To M. a Letter begun in Transit, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Torah Service, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Tov L'hodot, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
- U'vchen Ten Kavod, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Uvtsel Knafecha, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
- V'ani T'filati, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
- V-erastich Li, undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
- V'hayah B'achrit Haymim, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
- V'shamru, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Wedding Music, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Who are they to me, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Yaldah Yafah Achat, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Yiddish medley, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Yism'chu, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Y'shalem Adonai, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Yitro, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Zeh Hayom, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Zog nit kenmol, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Catalog of Music by Amindav Aloni, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Passages in Poetry, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Bottom Drawer Inventory, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Hallel, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
- 4 Sephardic Songs, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Gilgul shel Kaddish, undated (Box 18, Folder 9)
- New Hallel Score, undated (Box 12, Folder 15, Box 18, Folder 10)
- Gilgul Ha Kaddish Score, undated (Box 12, Folder 16, Box 18, Folder 11)
- Originals volume 1, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
- How fine you are - Song of Songs, undated (Box 18, Folder 12)
- Choral Score Hallel, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
- Hallel - Orchestra Score, undated (Box 18, Folder 13)
- Hallel, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Hallel - Orchestra parts, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Hallel Score - vellums, 1973 (Box 18, Folder 14)
- Steward's notes, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Ta'amei Sephard - percussion score, undated (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Circle of Love, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Torah Service, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Chassidic Service - vellums, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Cleveland Service, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Four settings from Shir hashirim, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Ner Shel Shabbat, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Or Ha-am, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
- String parts to Or Ha-am, undated (Box 13, Folder 12, Box 14, Folder 1)
- Or Ha-am Choral, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Or Ha-am Full Orchestra parts, undated (Box 14, Folder 3-5)
- Book of Ruth, undated (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
- Book of Ruth Score, undated (Box 18, Folder 15)
- Koheleth choral + piano, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
- Koheleth - Orchestra parts, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Koheleth - Original Instrument, vocal scores, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
- Koheleth parts, undated (Box 15, Folder 7, Box 16, Folder 1-3, Box 18, Folder 16)
- Mishpachah, undated (Box 16, Folder 4, Box 17, Folder 1)
- Ner shel Shabbat, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Score Or Ha-am, undated (Box 17, Folder 3)
- Or Ha-Am - Conductor score, undated (Box 17, Folder 4)
- Koheleth - Vellum, undated (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Or Ha-Am - score + narrator, undated (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Koheleth, undated (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Koheleth score, undated (Box 17, Folder 8)